Guide to the Northcutt Ely Papers, 1900-1982
Department of Special Collections
- Series 8. Oil and Gas files
  - Oil - Statistics1931 - 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    Re: petroleum industry, Federal Oil Conservation Board, predicted use of notor fuel and crude oil, Memoranda, correppondenco, spec she s, press releases, extracts from annual re arts, minutes of meetings of Technical & Advisory Committee, charts, reports, draft of documents. Correspondents,etc.: Ray Lyman Wilbur; E.S. Rochester; Scott Turner (Director, Bureau of Mines); Robert P. Lamont (Secty of Commerce)
  - Legal Memoranda1904 - 1922, Accession no. M0269 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    Re: abandoned military ruservations,cash entries, ceded Indian lands, changes af entry under the act of Jan, 27, 1922 (li2Stat,, 359), exchanges under the act of April 21, 1904 and Mar, 20, 1922, forest lieu selections, Indian homesteads, laws applicable to small holding claims, laws and decisions applicable to applications for fragmentary surveys of islands and erroneously omitted lands, military bounty land warants, preemption entries, private land claims, Scrip (public land laws), Soldiers Additional Rights Laws under which such rights exist, timber permits, townsitea, trade and manufacturing sites, unlawful enclosure, act of Feb. 27, 1925 (43 Stat,, 10134), act of Feb. 25, 1920 (41 Stat,, 437).
  - Oil - Imports - Tariff1931, 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    Re: tarriffs and embargos on petroleum importation, statistics regarding petroleum industry, regulation of commerce between U.S. and foreign countries in crude petroleum and produces thereof, S.J. Res. 238, 71st Congress, 3rd Session. Correspondence, press releases, bills, clippings. Correspondents, etc.: R.L. Wilbur; Robert L. O'Brien (Chairman Ways & Means Committee); H. Walker.
  - One binder containing memoranda for the Federal Oil Conservation Board re oil compacts suggestions, drafts of statutes, former compacts, and present laws 1931, Accession no. M0269 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Oil - Compact Colorado Springs1927, 1929, 1930, Accession no. M0269 (Box 99, Folder 6)
    Re: Petroleum Conference, Colorado Springs, interstate compacts, petroleum compacts. Correspondence, te1t~grams, memoranda, statement, speeches, minutes of Petroleum Conference, press releases, Correspondents, etc.: Northcutt Ely; M.L. Requa; Frank C. Emerson (Governor of Wyoming); Wm. E. Borah.
  - Oil - Compacts - Drafts of Agreements 1929, Accession no. M0269 (Box 99, Folder 7)
    Re interstate oil compacts. Correspondence, miscellaneous. Correspondents, etc.: Hines H. Baker (Humble Oil and Refining Co.).
  - Oil - Clippings1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 99, Folder 8)
    Re: regulation of production of oil and gas through interstate cooperation, oil conservation. Correspondence, press releases, newsclippings. Correspondents, etc.: C.O. Marshall (News Manager, United States Daily); Northcutt Ely
  - Oil Kettleman Hills1929 - 1931, Accession no. M0269 (Box 100, Folder 9)
    Re: North Dome, Kettleman Hills - agreements, -gas usuage, Act of July 3, 1930 (Public No. 527, 71st Congress) amended sections of 17 and 27 of Mineral Leasing Act, oil and gas prospecting permits. Correspondence, drafts of agreement, telegram, minutes of meetings, misc, Corre5pondents, etc.: ~inney (Solicitor, Dept. bf Interior Northcutt Ely; Ckorge Otis Smith; Ray Lyman Wilbur.
  - Oil - Mineral Leasing Act1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 100, Folder 10)
    Re: mineral leasing acts. Drafts of bill, bill S. 47lO, 72nd Congress, 1st Session, newsclippings, No. 4047 brief for the appellant (pamphlet)
  - Oil - Compacts - General1929, 1931, 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 100, Folder 11)
    Re: interstate oil conservation compacts. Correspondents, reports. Correspondents, etc.: .Northcutt Ely; C.B. Ames (Vice-President, Texas Co.); Wm, J. Kemnitzer (Director, Research Dept. in the Office of J. Edward Jones); E.S. Rochester
  - Oil - Legal Memos1929, Accession no. M0269 (Box 100, Folder 12)
    Re: State and interstate oil compacts. Report, memorandum, clipping from Congressional Record, photostatic prints of memoranda. Correspondents, etc.; W.R. Boyd Jr. (Executive Vice-President, American Petroleum Institute).
  - Oil - Public Domain1929, 1930, 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 100, Folder 13)
    Re: public lands, oil and gas prospecting permits on government lands. Correspondence, bill, photostatic copies of newsclippings, U.S. Supreme Court proceedings, Nos. 618, 676, 704, 743, memoranda, misc. Correspondents, etc.: R.L. Wilbur; N. Ely; Thomas C. Stawell(?) (Acting Commissioner, General Land Office); E.C. Finney
  - Oil Regulations of April 4, 19321932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 100, Folder 14)
    Re: regulations governing applications for oil and gas prospecting permits. Correspondence, memoranda, list of regulations. Correspondents, etc.: Ray Lyman Wilbur; N. Ely; Warwick N.. Downing (attorney).
  - Oil Pipe Linesn.d., Accession no. M0269 (Box 100, Folder 15)
    Re: legal matters regarding transportation of crude oil a~ by pipe line. Drafts of legislation, report, memorandum
  - Oil - PD Permits1929, 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 100, Folder 16)
    Re: oil prospecting permits. Correspondence, drafts of letters, press release. Correspondents, etc.: E.C. Finney; R.L. Wilbur; Herman Stabler (Chief, Conservation Division, Geological Survey); Commissioner of Land Office.
  - Oil - Oil States Advisory Committee1931 - 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 101, Folder 17)
    Re: interstate compacts, conservation of oil, Federal Oil Conservation Board. Correspondence, telegrams, draft of legislation, press release, misc. - Correspondents, etc.: Earl Oliver (Earl Oliver & Co., Petroleum Engineers); N. Ely; E.S. Rochester; Peter Q. Nyce ( of Long, Chamberlain & Nyce); Robert R. Penn (President, Penn Oil Co.); Cicero I. Murray (Chairman, Oil States Advisory Committee); Warwick N. Downing, Thurman Hill; Marvin Lee (petroleum Geologist); J.C. Van Eck (Shell Union Oil Corp.)
  - Oil - Legal Memos1929, 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 101, Folder 18)
    Re: proposed legislation respecting petroleum industry. Correspondence, misc. notes, typescripts of proceedings of cases. Correspondents, etc.: P.C. Black (Marland Oil Co.); James A, Veasey (Carter Oil Co.).
  - Oil - Decisionn.d., Accession no. M0269 (Box 101, Folder 19)
    Re: interstate oil compacts, petroleum and anti-trust laws final decision in court cases. Correspondence, memoranda, telegrams, drafts of compacts, photostatic copies or memoranda re: decisions in court cases, pamphlets. misc., newsclippings.
  - Oil Compact - H.R. 12076n.d., Accession no. M0269 (Box 101, Folder 20)
    Re: bills and acts for conservation of oil aid gas and providing for correlation of domestic and foreign production, bill 3.5258, Hal. 8897, HR. 10862, H.R. 10863, LR. 12070, pamphlet. Correspondence, telegrams, memoranda, bills, draft of legislative acts, reports, pamphlet, misc. Correspondents, etc.: N. Ely; Warwick X. Downing; Elizabeth Rowe, O.B. Miss; Cicero I. Murray,; Rochester; Ray Lyman Wilbur.
  - Oil Interstate Compacts1931 - 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 101, Folder 21)
    Re: interstate oil conservation compacts, acts for conservation of oil and gas and correlation of domestic and foreign production, list of compacts In chronological order bibliography of material dealing with laws of interstate compacts. Correspondence, memorandum, misc., newsclippings. Correspondents, etc.: W.M. Irish (President, Atlanta Refining Co.); Peter Q. Nice; N. Ely; E.S. Rochester.
  - Oil - Press Rele5ses and Clippings1929, Accession no. M0269 (Box 101, Folder 22)
    Re: misc. press releases and newsclippings, magazine clippings, Congressional Record Clippings, and correspondence re: bill. Correspondents, etc.: N. Ely; Alfred Farrell (Editor, The Bakersfield Californian); C.G. Marshall (News Mgr., The United States Daily); Allen's Press Clipping Bureau
  - Untitled1921, 1929, 1932, 1933, Accession no. M0269 (Box 102, Folder 23)
    Re: interstate oil compacts, constitutional powers of Congress over the uroduction of natural resources and their shipment in interstate commerce. Correspondence, draft of compact, notes re interstate oil compacts, reports, newsclippings, misc. Correspondents: Warwick M. Downing; N. Ely; Amos L. Beaty; Jesse H. Hones (Director, Reconstruction Finance Corp.); W.P.Z. German (attorney, Skelly Oil Co.); Allen Coat (U.S. District Judge, Baldwyn, Miss.); Lawrence Richey (Sectary to the President); Earl Oliver.
  - Untitledn.d., Accession no. M0269 (Box 102, Folder 24)
    Re: oil and gss pools. Map - East Texas Oil Field and other major oil field in U.S.; Pamphlet - world statutes legalizing agreements between operators for the cooperative development of oil and gas pools or for limitation of production during period of over-supply invalidate existing anti-trust laws or violate the fourteenth amendment to the U.S. Constitution.
  - Untitled1929, 1931, 1933, 1934, Accession no. M0269 (Box 102, Folder 25)
    Re: bills for conservation of oil and gas, interstate oil conservation compacts, otreroroduction of oil. Correspondence, press releases, draft of compacts, formal notes re compacbs, extract from annual reports, newsclippings. Correspondents, etc: William D. Mitchell (Attorney General), R.L. Wilbur; N. Ely; Thurman Hill; Kenner McConnel; E.B. Swanson (Chief Economist, Petroleum Economics Div., U.S. Dept. of Commerce); Thomas Moran(member Technical & Advisory Committee)
  - Untitled1920, 1921, 1932, 1933, Accession no. M0269 (Box 102, Folder 26)
    Re: oil ownership laws, Kettleman Development and production problems, oil wells, conservation of oil and gas, oil industry in general, figures re world gasoline trade, oil driilin~, refinery equipment. Correspondence, reports, speeches, press releases, news bulletin, statistical charts, pamphlets, newsclippings and magazine clippings. Correspondents, etc.: B.C. Rochester; O.P. Hood (Acting Director, Bureau of Mines); D.i3, Dow (Bureau of Mines); J.O Lewis; Francis C. Wilson.
  - Untitledn.d., Accession no. M0269 (Box 102, Folder 27)
    Re: misc. court cases involving oil companies.
  - Untitled1930, 1931, Accession no. M0269 (Box 102, Folder 28)
    Re: oil and gas prospecting permits, Kettleman Hills oil field. Correspondence, legal agreement, memoranda, photostatic copies of correspondence. Correspondents, etc.: N. Ely; J.H. Jenkins (Associated Oil Co.); J.V. Stair (Shell Oil Co.); R.R. Templeton (Pacific Western Oil Co.); R.E. Collom (Continental Oil Co.) R.A. Sperry (General Petroleum Corp. of Calif.); N.E. Lombardi (Standard Oil Co. of Calif.); C.E. Taber (Milham Exploration Co.); Elizabeth Rowe; Carl H. Beal (Petroleum geologist and engineer); James S. Bennett; Herman Stabler.
  - Untitled1930, 1931, Accession no. M0269 (Box 102, Folder 29)
    Re: Kettleman Hills oil and gas field. Correspondence, memos, draft of letters, press releases, legal agreements, drafts of agreements, newsclipping, telegrams. Correspondents, etc.: N. Ely; R.L. Wilbur; George W. Nilsson; William Reinhardt (General Mgr., Kettleman North Dome Association); Herman Stabler, E.C. Finney.
  - Untitled1931, 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 103, Folder 30)
    Re: Kettleman Hills oil and gas field, application of laws, waste of gas, oil and gas leases. Correspondence, statistics, legal agreements, memoranda. Correspondents, etc.: R.L. Wilbur; A.L. Weil (attorney); E.C, Finney; N. Ely.
  - Untitled1930, 1931, 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 103, Folder 31)
    Re: statistics respecting oil industry for specific time periods, gasoline situation abroad, crude and refined petroleum imports, crude oil production of the world. Correspondence, memorandum, press release, misc., statistic report. Correspondents, etc.: E.B. Swanson; R.L. Wilbur; N. Ely; Henry L. Doherty (Henry L. Doherty & Co.); E.3. Rochester.
  - Untitled1926, 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 103, Folder 32)
    Re: bill, conservation of oil and gas, correlation of domestic and foreign production (s. 5258), preliminary report of the Federal Oil Conservation Board to President of United States 1926, Report, press release, draft of legislative act,& bills, photostatic copy of bill.
  - Miscellaneous Text - Various court cases., Accession no. M0269 (Box 103, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Text - Various court cases., Accession no. M0269 (Box 103, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Text - Various court cases., Accession no. M0269 (Box 103, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous Notes., Accession no. M0269 (Box 103, Folder 36)
  - Drafts of Compacts1930, 1931, Accession no. M0269 (Box 103, Folder 37)
    Re: interstate oil compacts for conservation of oil and gas.
  - Miscellaneous court cases re oil drilling., Accession no. M0269 (Box 103, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous court cases re: pipe lines, taxing production of electric energy., Accession no. M0269 (Box 103, Folder 39)
  - Oil Shale - General1930, 1931, Accession no. M0269 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    Re: surface patent, oil shale-,cases, laws concerning oil shale bands, bill H.R. 17338. Correspondence, memoranda, press release, bill, newsclippings. Congressional Record clippings, misc. Correspondents, etc.: N. Ely; Malcolm Lindsey (lawyer); Charles S. memos (lawyer); R.L. Wilbur; C.C. Moore (Commissioner, General Land Office); Don B. Colton (Committee on the Public Lands
  - Untitledn.d., Accession no. M0269 (Box 104, Folder 40)
    Re: various court cases involving drilling, leases, taxes, pipe lines, texts re investigation of oil shale situation.
  - Untitled1920 - 1930, Accession no. M0269 (Box 104, Folder 42)
    Re: charts of oil patents issued in Colorado from 8/9/20 - ll/25/24 and 10/2/26 - 9/29/30, employee leave record for Ralph 5, Kelley (Chief of Field Division) for 1930 and employee leave request forms completed by Kelly for 1930.
  - Untitled1930, 1931, Accession no. M0269 (Box 104, Folder 43)
    Re: Ralph 0, Kelley (government employee who made charges of mal-administration of oil shale lands against the Dept. of Interior, specifically Ray Lyman Wilbur, Secretary of the Interior).
  - Oil shale - Justice1926, 1930, Accession no. M0269 (Box 104, Folder 44)
    Correspondence re laws respecting oil shale claims
  - Untitled1928, 1930, Accession no. M0269 (Box 104, Folder 45)
    Re Oil shale - legal cases, oil shale patents, ruport from Oil Conservation Board, Ralph S. Kelley. Misc. text, newsclipninsg, report.
  - Oil - Unit Operation1931, Accession no. M0269 (Box 104, Folder 46)
    Re: oil unit operations (oil or gas pools), anti-trust laws, economics of oil production methods, utilization of gas energy. Reports, correspondence, pamphlet. Correspondents, etc.: N. Ely; Roger J. J. Traynor (Calf. Law Review); W.P.Z. German; Geo. Otis Smith; Col. Wm. J. Donovan; R.F. MacArthur; H.M. Stalcup; J.R. McWilliams, Earl Oliver
  - Untitled1929, 1932, 1933, Accession no. M0269 (Box 104, Folder 47)
    Report - The Interdependence of States in Oil Conservation proposed uniform act for oil and natural gas conservation and interstate compact; proposed interstate compact for oil conservation; press release re appointment of Ely as executive secretary. to the Secretary of the interior
  - Untitled1921, 1930, Accession no. M0269 (Box 105, Folder 48)
    Re: Ralph S. Kelley and scandal concerning oil shale lands Photostatic copies of newsclippings and chronological table of oil shale matters, excerpts from diary of' Governor Moore re Kelley and the oil shale lands, misc. notes.
  - Report - Examination into the charges of Ralph S. Kelley respecting the administration of oil shale lands...Oct. 24, 1930, Accession no. M0269 (Box 105, Folder 49)
  - Report - Examination into the charges of Ralph S. Kelley respecting the administration of oil shale lands...Oct. 24, 1930, Accession no. M0269 (Box 105, Folder 50)
  - Report - Examination into the charges of Ralph S. Kelley respecting the administration of oil shale lands...Oct. 24, 1930, Accession no. M0269 (Box 105, Folder 51)
  - Printed correspondence between Ralph 3, Kelley and various people1930, 1925, Accession no. M0269 (Box 105, Folder 52)
  - Untitled1928, 1930, 1931, Accession no. M0269 (Box 106, Folder 53)
    Re: laws concerning oil claims (various court cases) in connection with R.L. Wilbur and Ralph S. Kelley, bill re annual assessment upon oil shale lands, charts re oil shale and outcrop. Correspondence, press releases, photostatic copies re court cases, bill H.R. 12802
  - Untitled1930, 1931, Accession no. M0269 (Box 106, Folder 54)
    Re: oil shale, Ralph S. Kelley, statements by Wilbur re the charges made against him by Kelley (Freeman-Summers Case). Misc., and detailed texts, press releases, correspondence, memos, telegrams, photostatic copies of newsclippings, S. Res. 379. Correspondents, etc.: R.L. Wilbur, N. Ely, LD. White; Jouett Shouse; Charles Nichelson; F.B. Knapp
  - Untitled1928, 1929, 1930, Accession no. M0269 (Box 106, Folder 55)
    Re: oil shale patents, Ralph S. Kelley and the oil shale land issue. Correspondence, misc. notes, statistics. Correspondents, etc.: N. Ely; C.C. Moore; Seth N. Richardson (Assistant Attorney General)
  - Newsclippings re Ralph S. Kelley and the oil shale land issue, Accession no. M0269 (Box 106, Folder 56)
  - Untitled1930, 1931, Accession no. M0269 (Box 106, Folder 57)
    Re: Land Office regulations, excerpt from Commissioner Moore's diary re Kelley, un-patented oil shale claims. Correspondence and misc., photostatic copies of checks from Treasurer of U.S. made out to Ralph S. Kelley. Correspondents, etc.: R.L, Wilbur; Thomas C. Hawell (Acting Commissioner, General Land Office)
  - Oil Shale - Decisions by Wilbur1929 - 1930, Accession no. M0269 (Box 106, Folder 58)
    Photostatic copies of Wilbur's oil shale decisions from March 4, 1929 to Oct. 1, 1930.
  - Re: oil shale, some re: Wilbur to Kelley.1928, 1930, Accession no. M0269 (Box 106, Folder 59)
    Excerpts from reports from Federal Oil Conservation Board Report. Pamphlet, correspondence, misc. Correspondents, etc.: Ray Lyman Wilbur.
  - Untitled1935, Accession no. M0269 (Box 107, Folder 60)
    Re: regulations governing oil and gas operations on restricted Indian lands in Oklahoma, laws regulating interstate and foreign commerce in petroleum, legislative acts, Correspondence, typescripts, reports, pamphlet, newsclipping. Correspondents, etc.: illegible.
  - Untitled1933, 1938, Accession no. M0269 (Box 107, Folder 61)
    Re: regulation of oil industry, Connally Act, U.S, vs. Standard Oil Co. court case, Lists and notes of various court cases, chronology of events, correspondence.
  - Untitled1933, 1936, 1938, Accession no. M0269 (Box 107, Folder 62)
    Re: conservation of oil and gas, drilling, laws concerning Indian property, cost of alcohol motor fuel; comparison of oil and gas laws, Correspondence, reports, pamphlet, photostatic copies of correspondence and reports. Correspondents, etc.: H.H. Power (Professor, University of Texas); N. Ely; Thurman Arnold; Arthur R. Campbell (Secretary-Treas., Mid-Continent Oil and Gas Assoc,); James A. Veasey (Vice-Pres, Carter Oil Co.); J. Elmar Thomas; Frank Phillips; John W. Frey.
  - Untitled1938, 1939, 1940, Accession no. M0269 (Box 107, Folder 63)
    Re: conservation of petroleum (Bill, R.H. 7372), report from National Resources Board to the President re conservation of minerals, laws and oil production, oil drilling units, oil refineries, Connally Act, H. Res. 290, 291,estimate of petroleum reserves. Correspondence, reports, pamphlets, newsclippings. Correspondents, etc.: N. Ely; A.H. Cornell; Joseph E. Pogue (Interstate Oil Compact Committee); Frank Phillips (Phillips Petroleum Co.); A.M. Walker (Interstate Oil Compact Committee); John D. Frey (U.S. Dept. Interior, Petroleum Conservation Division); R.B.F, Hummer (Phillips Petroleum Co.); A,M. Crowell (Dept. of Conservation, Arkansas); A.R, Campbell; Robert B, Luick (Harvard Univ.); Howard L, Bevis (Harvard Univ.); W.L. Summers; Roy N. Johins (Atlantic Refining Co.).
  - History of Federal Petroleum Legislation1938, Accession no. M0269 (Box 107, Folder 64)
    Correspondence, report, misc. Correspondents, etc.: P.C. Spencer (Consolidated Oil Corp and Chairman, Oil Subcommittee); N. Ely; R.E. Coliom; Ann Koehler (Cravath, Dc Gersdorff, Swaine & Wood); W.C. Mendenhall (Director, Geological Survey); James L. Shepherd; W. Henry Rector; W.P.Z. German; Floyd A. Calvert; Hiram M. Dow; Robert E. Hardwicke
  - Untitled1929 - 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 108, Folder 65)
    Re: Kettleman Hills North Dome Agreement, oil drilling, permits, various court cases involving oil companies. Correspondence, drafts of bills. Correspondents, etc.: N. Ely; E,J. Rochester, R.L, Wilbur; Herman Stabler; Julian D, Sears (Acting Director Geological Survey)
  - Untitled1931 - 1933, Accession no. M0269 (Box 108, Folder 66)
    Re: oil conservation, oil pools, bills re interstate oil compacts (H.R. 10862, 10863), Correspondence, memos, drafts of compacts, bills, misc., press release. Correspondents, etc.: C.C. Moore; N.. Ely; Henry L. Doherty; C.B. Ames; Dwight L. Wilbur, M.D
  - Untitledn.d., Accession no. M0269 (Box 108, Folder 67)
    Newsclippings re relief aid to small oil operations, oil conservation program, oil importation, tariffs
  - Untitled1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 108, Folder 68)
    Re: interstate compacts, drafts of legislative bills, Correspondence, telegrams, misc, Correspondents, etc.: N.Ely; Kenner McConnell (attorney); Warwick N, Downing; Cicero I, Murray (Chairman, Oil States Advisory Committee)
  - Notes re various court eases mostly involving oil drilling and oil conservation, Accession no. M0269 (Box 108, Folder 69)
  - Untitled1930 - 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 108, Folder 70)
    Re: oil tariffs, drafts of conservation bills, invitations to conferences, crude oil statistics 1910-1931, bill S. 581. Correspondence, telegrams, memo, draft of act. Correspondents, etc.: N, Ely; E.S, Rochester; R,L. Wilbur; James A. Veasey; Walter C, Woodward; E,C. Finney; C~B. Ames
  - Untitled1931 - 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 109, Folder 71)
    Re: oil importation, curtailment of oil production, draft of legislative act for conservation of oil and gas, bill S. 5258 for conservation of oil and gas; legislative control of business of producing oil and gas. Correspondence, memos, pamphlet, magazine clippings, misc. Correspondents, etc.: N. Ely; Thurman Hill; Peter Q. Nyce
  - Articles and speeches re interstate assistance for oil; overproduction, oil conservation interstate compacts, petroleum industry, public domain. (N. Ely; James 0. Lewis, Petroleum Engineer; Felix Frankfurter; James H. Landis; Robert P. Lamont; Herman Stabler; G.W. Holland; J.F. Deeds; W.P.Z. German; Francis C. Wilson., Accession no. M0269 (Box 109, Folder 72)
  - Articles and speeches re oil industry; oil and gas conservation, mineral industry, methods of attaining oil, legislative proposals re oil industry, economic law in petroleum industry. (W.S. Farish; George Otis Smith; Grant B. Battelle; John N. Lovejoy; Joseph H. Pogue; Max W. Ban.), Accession no. M0269 (Box 109, Folder 73)
  - One binder containing interstate oil compact data, Accession no. M0269 (Box 109, Folder 74)
  - Untitled1931 - 1932, Accession no. M0269 (Box 109, Folder 75)
    Re: occurrence of petroleum in North America, reports from Federal Conservation Board, conservation of oil and gas stabilizing oil industry.
- Series 9. Water Irrigation files
  - Subseries 1. Boulder Dam
    - Correspondence, blueprints, clippings, legal briefs re: All American Canal contract, Colorado River Dam fund, Malewind Will case, and the Packer Dam contract, 1931 - 1933, Accession no. M0269 (Box 110, Folder 1)